photofeeler.com 2019-04-04

# Privacy Policy

PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY POLICY CAREFULLY BEFORE USING THIS SITE.

By visiting and engaging with this site in any way (with or without an account), you signify your assent to the Privacy Policy ("policy"). If you do not agree, unfortunately you cannot use this site. This is standard practice, and it is your responsibility to be aware of and abide by it.

The Photofeeler team ("Photofeeler") may revise and update this policy at any time. Your continued usage of the Photofeeler.com website ("site") will mean you accept those changes.

**1\. What information do we collect?**

When registering on our site, rating photos, or testing photos, as appropriate, we collect information from you in order to provide and improve upon our service. It's apparent, first of all, that you can post images to Photofeeler.

We also may collect your:

  * First name
  * Email address
  * Birth date or birth year
  * Gender

Additionally, if you register using Facebook or LinkedIn, you may be asked for further information specific to your Facebook or LinkedIn account. (Typically this will include your public profile information.) It is Facebook and LinkedIn's responsibility that a list of this information be shown to you, so that you can accept or deny those requests at the time of registration.

You may optionally provide us with occupation-related information when adding a context label to Business images in which you are the photo subject.

**2\. What do we use your information for?**

We collect your email address in order to send periodic emails, to contact you in regards to your Photofeeler account, and to identify your account. Do note that you may unsubcribe from our periodic emails at any time, using the link at the bottom of any email you've received from us.

We collect your first name, gender, and birth date or year in order to customize your experience, ensure that the correct photos are shown to the correct users, and to conduct research. 

If you optionally choose to label a Business photo of yourself with a description of what you do for work, Photofeeler provides this context to targeted users so that they may rate photos more accurately.

Any actions performed on Photofeeler are collected and retained as a core function of providing and maintaining our service and may be used without identifying information in scientific research.

**3\. Deletion of personal data**

Account deletion is as laid out in our Terms of Use. To have an account registration deleted, use this form to contact customer service.

Some information associated with deleted accounts is retained in order to maintain the service for other users, for statistical and historical purposes, and for use in scientific research.

**4\. We do not disclose any information to outside parties except as per your request.**

Except in the case of a merger or acquisition, your information, whether public or private, will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any other company for any reason whatsoever, without your consent, other than for the express purpose of delivering the purchased product or service requested.

This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

**5\. How we protect your information**

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you submit or access your personal information.

We offer the use of a secure server. All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our payment gateway providers database only to be accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential.

After a transaction, sensitive information (such as credit card numbers) are never stored on our servers.

**6\. What is our use of cookies?**

When you visit the site, a session ID cookie is placed on your computer that only lasts while you're visiting. We also place persistent cookies (also known as local storage devices) to make the login experience faster and easier.

You may set your browser and your mobile settings to block cookies and local storage devices, but if you do so, you may not be able to access all of our features.

Photofeeler uses cookies and local storage devices for a number of reasons, including to ensure the security of our app and site, to provide you with features you have requested and to analyze how members and visitors use the site. Use typically falls into three categories:

those that are strictly necessary to deliver the services and products you have requested

cookies related to the performance of the app or site, such as analytics that help us determine how our app or site is performing and ensuring a smooth and trouble free experience for our members and visitors

third parties cookies that also relate to functionality, such as Facebook login

These cookies and local storage devices provide the functionality that our Photofeeler members enjoy.

In some cases, the app or site feature you choose, such as Facebook login, may allow a third party to place cookies or local storage devices on your computer. The third party who places cookies on your device is responsible for how they process their data and Photofeeler recommends that you read their privacy policies.

Our use of cookies and local share devices, including the specific cookie names, may change over time.

**Effective date**

Our privacy policy was last updated on: May 24, 2018.
